

# **CONTACT**

Address
Grillenberg 1
3160 Traisen
Austria

**Phone number** +43 68184013023

Email lisa.hollaus@live.at

GitHub https://github.com/LisaHollaus

# SKILLS

# **Technical:**

- Python: OOP, Databases, Networking, Django, Concurrency
- R: Statistics, Visualization
- Web: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, JavaScript
- Networking: Cisco Packet Tracer, Wireshark
- Databases: SQLite, SQLAlchemy, neo4j

## **Analytical:**

- Data Analysis
- Project Management
- Organizational Skills

# Soft:

- Adaptability
- Communication
- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork
- Cultural Awareness

# **Hollaus Lisa-Maria**

# Informatics Student

# **PROFILE**

As a passionate student currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in informatics (with a focus on Data Science at IMC University of Applied Science), my background includes not only technical skills and various work experiences, but also a unique 1.5-year period of traveling across Europe, Northern and Central America between 2021 and 2023, enriching my adaptability and broadening my global perspective.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Agricultural worker

Restaurant ('Most-Buschenschank') and organic farm Hollaus Traisen. Austria

www.grillenberg.at

Seasonal work

- Production of home-grown juice, sirup, jam, liqueur, schnaps,...
- Food and beverages service

#### Farm hand

Workaway

Hegranes, Iceland

- Animal care (sheeps, horses, ducks, cats and dogs)
- Baking and cooking for the family
- Basic household chores

#### **Office Assistant**

**District Chamber of Farmers** 

Lilienfeld, Austria

- InfoPoint
- Assistance with Funding applications
- Transferring data; digitization

# Confectioner (including apprenticeship)

**Bakery Florian Hink** 

Wilhelmsburg, Austria

https://www.florian-hink.at/

Employed in all fields including:

- Basic Austrian sweets production
- Baking and decorating cakes for special events
- Ice-cream production
- Pralines manufacture
- Seasonal work like Christmas cookies,...

11/2021 – 12/2021

09/2020 - 09/2023

(not consistently)

03/2021 - 05/2021

09/2016 - 09/2020

#### **Practical:**

- Agriculture & Food Production
- Animal Care
- Childcare & Home Care

# **LANGUAGES**

German (Mother tongue) English (Level C1 – main language at university) Spanish (Beginner)

# **HOBBIES**

- Hiking
- Cooking and Baking
- Travelling
- Learning new skills
- Reading

# **INTERNSHIPS**

#### Home care aid

05/2016 - 07/2016

Volkshilfe Traisen & Nursing home Türnitz

Austria

- Sustain and support physical, mental and social well-being
- Obtaining the household
- Documentation

# **Kindergarten Assistant**

11/2015

Kindergarten Kirchengasse

Traisen, Austria

- Supporting the kindergarten carer
- Encourage and motivate the children
- Settle disputes

Service

07/2015 - 08/2015

09/2017 - 02/2021

Confectionary Felbermayer

Lilienfeld, Austria

- Taking orders (beverage and food)
- Serve Austrian desserts, ice-cream and coffee variations
- Dealing with bill payments

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

**UNIVERSITY** 2023 – Present

Informatics bachelor's degree program (3. Semester)

IMC University of Applied Science

Krems an der Donau, Austria

Computer Science focused on Data Science

'BERUFSREIFEPRÜFUNG'

(A-Level - general qualification for university entrance)

Berufsförderungsinstitut (BFI)

St.Pölten, Austria

https://www.bfinoe.at/

**Evening-classes** 

APPRENTICESHIP 2016 – 2018

Confectioner

**Bakery Florian Hink** 

Wilhelmsburg, Austria

https://www.florian-hink.at/

# **TECHNICAL SCHOOL (3 years)**

2013 – 2016

Skilled worker for agriculture- and household-management

Fachschule Sooß

Sooß, Austria

Graduating with "Mittlere Reife" (GCSE), as well as:

- ECDL (European Computer Driving License)
- HACCP certificate
- Allergy-training-course
- Kindergarten assistant
- Home-helper
- Medical office assistant with diploma course
- Baby Fit (Babysitter)
- First-aid course

#### **SECONDARY SCHOOL**

Traisen, Austria

# **ELEMENTARY SCHOOL**

Traisen, Austria

2009 – 2013

2005 - 2009

# TRAVEL EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2023

- 14 months long solo travel across northern Europe, Iceland, Northern and Central America
- Engaged in cultural exchanges and intercultural work experiences through 'Workaway'
- 4.5 months long solo walk (pilgrimage) from Austria to Spain in 2023
- Developed strong adaptability, communication, and problem-solving skills through immersion in various environments